Hey, de there we are live at but...here...build.
Pretty exciting there's some really good announcements I...tweet by the way this is...my good friend hello do
you work on...on visual studio and all the...tool in visual web
tooling visual so-so it...this anecdote eyes there was this guy who
did a tweet is like hey I'm coming back to javascript development after six months of doing.
My goodness everything is different what's changed in the last six
months when it comes to developing for the web and javascript in the last six
months probably not that much like drastically ios ogg yeah,
things move fast that's for sure, yeah, so, especially in our stack we're now see this adoption
envision studio of the node base tools and our and pm the page managers and...
gulp to task runners ok...is minute find bundle...javascript files compile
type script so on and that sort of runs...and cross-platform and right and it's a
very different world especially for like maybe the typical visual studio user of has...so,
in that sense a lot of stuff has happened new frameworks come up,...it's there's a human there's so many
things to keep track of when it comes to web development so
I'm just going to start naming some things and let's see if we could put them in
the appropriate buckets...and pm what is that
package manager node package manager ok bauer.
That's of client-side library package manager so it's
a so they're both package manager guess what's yours...and pm...well, so,
there are fundamental differences but they're also very similar we can let's just take new good in
...well because they'll see that are...three package measures we now have to deal with right just let's
...them apart a little bit so new get that we know...many years have
providers with both server-side components like dl files but also
...act of like j query and bootstrap angular js, you know,
for the client-sideso, in the new...on
...five new good will only be handling the server-side components like the
...the assemblies the dl files...but they will not it will not handle client-side
packages anymore so for that we want to use bauer because that's our climb side
...now...was really cool about
it is that our is a lot larger has a lot more packages available the new
good has for the client-side space and that's also where,
you know, people that actually build the frameworks they put they put it on our so
that's always up-to-date as a huge ecosystem sort of it's a great gain
for us visual student dot net developers that we have access to those natively with envisions
...now because we just have more options and,
that's great...overlap between and pm and bauer yes so
what how we look at it is internally envisions the we kind of treat and pm
...a way to bring in tooling so...assemblies our for
...sideline...in pm for tooling okay what do you mean by...
yeah, so, that would...stuff that helps you run tasks on your
app like help you compile lists and...and coffee script and
...help you minute find bundle your javascript...I can help with all
...think about imis...right that's sort of a tooling thing we now have these things called
...and gulp you install them into your project using and pm and ios
maggots manager so but they're still like they're still like...little bit of
...because...a lot of overlap you will find client-side packages on
...pm like the same ones...on bauer so if you want to use I just want
to use and p it doesn't have as many client-side packages what more people actually putting
clarissa pages on...pm so you could say I'm just going to use and pm for both client-side packages
and potentially if you want to your build orchestration stuff...tooling
well, that makes a little bit more...and pm and bauer and new get...all
...the same family new get for assemblies and pm to bring in tooling
...and then...client-side frameworks that's right like angular
etc it's all right so now that we've gotten gone through those three so,
we have we have and pm bauer and new get now we have
run and
...one of those yet...are the ones that we bring in using and
...a couple of tooling components so grunt...kind of
solve the same problem of orchestrating or running tasks on your client-side
app so I was mentioning like stuff like compiling lessons...coffee script or bundling
...stuff like that and what really cool about this is that because we install them
into in our project individual project just like
...all-new pegs that's to this specific project right what?
Happens...that you can have a specific version of a compiler.
In that one project a different version another project and they
...it's okay and that's perfectly fine right so you can
...tooling sort of the compiles all that follow the project so that's new world sort of right so,
it if you're doing any...five.
...all that stuff where we also have like
the idea of shipping the actual runtime...the...is in there and now the client
service so you'll be able to reliably work on stuff without things messing
up with that basically means that your entire...now is completely isolated and can be worked
on by multiple people, you know, shared across get what we are
bigger team or whatever and you always know that the tool is going to be the same so that music
runt and gulp what is the role...they do so they they're the ones that
...with compiling and fondling and magnification and
...sort of client-side
...you might have looked at any task so...taking your less and converting in this
...or taking your type script averting
into javascript exactly okay so now that we've sort of got a framework we understand that
and p bauer and new get our for...and packages and then
grunt and gulp...for running tasks how do you make this magic happen when
you're using visual studio and that's where you come right yes so we had
we talk about is like...actually long-time background so we
have some ideas we had to make sure that these tools which are you
...primarily used on the command-line today we have to make sure that they would when they
were like used within visual studio that the command-line...still work in the exact same way I got
there would be no visual studio specifics needed to consume these new tools right and,
that the user can opt out saying I don't want to use which
is due to handle any of this I'll just do it on the command-line or...don't want to use it at
...you have we have completely divested ourselves of the not invented
here syndrome and...you said it works their
...use those tools yep but with one big difference right let's see if we were going to do
anything in visual studio on top of this stuff it had to be a better experience then what's what
...out there today usually command-line...you got...shows yes...so?
Here I have a project...pretty empty is...five...and,
I thought let's just build a really small little static website...okay so?
I'm just going to add a index dot html so let's do that.
...all...that was cleverness that stuff
you built to that could be web essentials that might be it but I think actually
is building ok...little hidden snippet ...let's say that I want
...to build this is website writer and I want to add bootstrap so
...client-side css framework right to
makings fit nicely and be respond responsive web and, you know,
it's I like that framework...lot-of frameworks like them out there like...but, you know,
but, service...one so now want to
...in using bauer ok so what I want to do is I want to create.
A powered adjacent file that is the equivalent if you're familiar with new get that
equivalent of packages that conflict okay,
so, we're going to create powder json.
In the root of the project here there's like a really cool little icon there at the bottom
...show you we know what your using...well it's because that
...we're ending up with a lot of json files and the
jason's sort of looks like similar and it looked like so having a little like on
...business form of essentials...I'm just experimenting with this...got like.
So, what really cool is that we have this new jason editor in visual studio and we can now see here that we get like
...that's the that's I think?
That's where the experience get better because if you're typing this
...just a regular edit right you're going to have to be fumbling around make sure you type in the right
...you getting these definitions from well if we take a look up here we can see that
there's a url.
schemas dot org iso schemas dot org has like a lot of different
...schema files its open-source the cool thing is that any schema that is on
there visual studio will automatically apply.
To a file that has specific name that's matched up to that schema file so like in this case we know that
powered adjacent matches this url this schema
guidance schema store so if there's like some new with bang z that comes out we'll
...as long as it's in the jason's...store we don't have to update vision
...all just set up a...schemas dot org and...to go that's on
...side no right because it seems like...actually really cool art
up all right so we need to give it a name your.
Whatever and web application thirty-eight is the right
...I whatever...look here you get like nys.
Descriptions and all that sort of all coming and
...the brackets because it knows it needs and...object and everything it's a really,
really great experience typing and...you don't need to put in the quotes and all that kind of just...that so let's
do bootstrap look here how you get like intelligence from...in, you know,
...registry online awesome and we can do that so that's the latest version I'm
going to now save this file.
...check out what's happening here is...magic's does something here's
...app in your magic and something is happening here in the manager locker pegged it
looks like it's calling bauer it's not that...not embedding something you're not
ok so that's running and we can see dependencies up here.
...get our...now see bootstrap is install and has a dependency and
decor right and that's all been brought down to us...dependencies handled by...itself so that
super-rich...so we just type what I wanted I got intelligence work and I just save the
file and that's it that's it right the like normally if you would do this and the command-line you have to open
the command-line you would know what the name...baggage was and the version potentially if you
...the latest so on now we just say...file this is...yeah,
That's really nice if we look at the
...the structure here we can see...have our components, yeah, that's the standard way
...bauer store stuff you can change that to be a different location
of different name but by default our installs into our underscore
component and if you want to change that you have to go into the bauer configuration, yeah, you can just basically
...our cdot par...file and you can configure that and keep that in your project and that will
...honor that and that speaks more towards us respecting
with bowers doing because it's doing fine yes whatever, whatever our however
bauer works is how wishes to works on top of got it right because underneath
everything visual studio does is just acting like a proxy between you and the command-line got it
...then they anything that happens in visual studio visual studio...command-line
So, anyway, we can see here that we have our bootstrap and we have these different things but,
we don't have the our components over here so we actually height that.
...for show it by say show his of the...and it shows up right here because you don't want to be messing with
...bowers and control, yeah,
well, you could you just uses...consume everything that's
in our components but what I like to do is that I like to use gulp that I can
set up task that copies just the fonts...live...hours about...and put it into my
avid location I want...our start to see the difference we use bauer to
bring in part of the ui stuff that we're doing and we're going to use goal is that
using rooms gulp to take that just the stuff we want out of our components when we
can compile or sort of movies this thing exactly so in order to install gulp that's
tooling right where use and pm...right so in pm this is very similar package dot
json we at that file and now we get the exact same experience
A version.
And, nieces some ver
...looks like this and then we need dependencies actually we
need the dependencies doesn't really matter and we're going to get got
And,...through that and I'm going to save this...happening I just say
for honk magic is now underway are sleeves people...parsley and...pm now shows up your
...awesome okay so it's installing the background sorta is not done yet
...a zero here so working on slower.
So, that means we now bring in the tool gulp and if you look at that in the.
File explore we have called in the node modules folder...and again
we don't show node modules over here because this you probably don't
want to have in your app again there could be teachers where you do but,
you know, what's...tool...might...it's yeah, if that's what you're using it for exactly
so now we just have to create a gulp file dot js now this
is where gulp that's sort of its initial file it has to be
...file js and I love the we have a little
...nautical...
Holy cal not-so-little you get a little
...the snippet so what I'm going to do not going to use gulp to create a task
that copies bootstrap from our components into my file
...verge my project so I'm going to say gulp source.
And, you're going to use this for most of the...file so-called...to do.
And, this right here means.
...the root directory so we're going to take our components.
And, we're going to take bootstraps so.
I kinda know what you're right here right I know what
this so I'm going to say anything that's inside the...
...this is a glossing pattern so I'm going to take all that I'm going to
hype that knows how you get intelligence are really rich intelligence...
gulp dot destinations of this or creates this is a streaming system so this kind
...this helper built this nation that sort of the file stream that
...the on-disk and we're just going to give that a destination so let's create new
...lip and bootstrap.
Just like that.
I'm going to save this file so now.
We have the new task...all...cools zoom...that's cool right.
So, now we can just execute that has...created.
Copyright here.
It...you may...I...make sure that everyone can see that
were just literally running gulp yes I mean it's not it's not like we
...anything this is goal this is the output of a node js process.
So, we see we ran it and we now have a lip folder with a boutros folder and
we have all this stuff up here right now that's awesome so very cool and just to make sure that you see
here how we're not actually be...doing anything that's not already support if
we just open the command-line your I can just...gulp let me just
Gulp copy.
Let's execute that and we see we get the...same output...is...not doing anything magical they're just
...our the same way you...so that's important to keep in mind.
...pretty cool you're right,
yeah, is there anything else...here's my question what's...grunt and goal
the same it seems like gulp is more code oriented and grunt is more
...definition oriented is...good assessment, yeah,
that's one way of looking at I think there's so, I think...was sort of the first one out there and it was the one that
sort of revolutionized the client-side workflow adult came a little later and was
build on different principles like everything is a stream right and if you treat everything
is a stream it's very easy to orchestrate different things so you might orchestrate things like the first thing you
do is that you find a source file...less file and,
you want...rather compiler on it right so you hyped that stream that
fashion to less compiler that again return to stream that has the compile
...and you can run that to...auto prefix or to a...fire?
And, then at the end you can put it on...right with the gulp tests
...offense you can orchestrate very cool
way like that so gulp gives you that grunt does not in run...a little bit different and you know,
that's fine whatever whichever one you like we have equal support for them so that's awesome, yeah,
so, just to finish up is this something that you can
use and now is or isn't something you have to use visual studio twenty fifteen
for so the best experience here you get with visions two-twenty fifteen
okay there are however extensions out there for with visions two-twenty
thirteen ok so there's the task explore so this entire
...you see down here from this one is out for visual studio
twenty thirteen as a free download...is not
...full featured as this but most of it you get so, that's good that's one of them the other
one is called package intelligence and that's one that give you like the our
and pm intelligence in the...that is
...school that when you save the file automatically app installswhen you open
the project for the first-time and you don't have like the say the node modules in the
our components folder because you just cloning from get up and didn't check in those files will
automatically restore those packages for-you that's twenty fifteen stuff that no that, yeah, that's why that's
...twenty fifteen but you can get it that's also in the package intelligence got it
...two-twenty thirteen so if you go to visual studio gallery dot com that's our we have all
are extensions package intelligence and...and grunt launcher
...launcher is...gives you some right click context menu...the solution
explore to do some things that...don't need that and two-twenty fifteen...a built-in yes
...except for one thing but that's coming all right...thanks so much refunding some time was sort of the
miss defying all these tools for client-side javascript development manages a pleasure
...thanks for watching and we'll see in...